Monica,which of all of this kitchen stuff is mine?
廚房有哪些東西是我的？
This bottle opener.
這個開罐器
-And...? -And it's a magnet.
還有呢？ 還有上面的磁鐵
Look at that!
你看
How weird is that? You're moving in with me...
多巧啊 你要搬來跟我住
and you have the one thing I don't have.
而我就缺一個開罐器
It's like, in a way, you complete me.
彷彿是你讓我變得完整
-Kitchen. -What?
我是說廚房 什麼？
You complete me kitchen, matey!
你讓我的廚房變得完整，室友
I know what you're thinking.
羅斯，我知道你在想什麼
That she'll move in with you, then fall in love with you, and then...
她搬去跟你住之後 或許會愛上你
when she finds out you're already married, she'll be happy.
等她發現你們還有婚姻關係 就會很高興
You know? You're just very sad.
你真的很悲哀
Oh,my God!
我的天哪
I see what this is. You are in love with Rachel!
我終於知道了，你愛上瑞秋了
It all adds up! You're obsessed with her. It's always:
什麼？ 沒錯，這就對了，你迷戀她
"What will you do about Rachel? Why are you moving in with Rachel?
「羅斯，瑞秋的事怎麼辦」 「羅斯，你為何要跟瑞秋住」
When will you confess your secret marriage to Rachel?" You want her!
「你何時要承認沒辦註銷」 你想要她
亂講
Saved by the bell.
電話救了你一命…
Aren't these candlesticks mine?
瑞秋，這對燭台不是我的嗎？
No,I bought those.
不，那是我買的
Oh, right. I forgot.
對喔，我忘了
That you're a liar!
忘了你是個騙子
That's great! I'll be there Monday. And thank you again.
不會，太好了，我星期一過去 再次謝謝你，好的
That was the head of the paleontology department...
是紐約大學 古生物學的
at N...
系
Y...
主
U.
任
Wow. What...
他
did he...
說
say?
什麼？
Remember that paper I had published last year on sediment flow rate?
記得我那篇沉積速率論文嗎？
-They loved it. -Well, who wouldn't?
他們很喜歡 有誰會不喜歡？
I know!
就是嘛
Anyway,they asked me to be a guest lecturer.
總之他們要聘我當客座教授
It's temporary, but if they like me, it could lead to a full-time job.
是暫時的 但表現得好就可能轉任正職
How great would that look on the mailbox? Professor Geller.
標在信箱上可帥了：蓋勒教授
Professor and Mrs.
是啊，教授與夫人
And Mrs.?
與夫人？
You and Ross are still married.
對，你和羅斯還是夫妻
What?
什麼？
Just kidding!
開玩笑的啦
Oh,God!
天哪
Saved your ass.
救了你的狗命
The One Where Joey Loses His lnsurance
本集播出：「裝腔作調」
rainystar壓制iPod-MP4
What's the matter?
怎麼了？
You know that psychic I see?
我不是有在找靈媒？ 是啊
She told me I'm gonna die this week, so I'm bummed.
她說我這個星期會死 所以我有點沮喪
I know you don't know about readings, but that's the worst you can get.
什麼？ 我知道你們不太懂通靈術 但這應該算是最糟的預言
That's crazy.
這太誇張了
She'd say that to you?
她居然咒你死
You don't believe her, do you?
你不會相信吧？
I don't know. She said that I'd have triplets...
她預言過我會生三胞胎
but she also said one of them would be black.
但她也說會有一個黑寶寶
Just out of curiosity, did she say how you'd go?
純屬好奇：她有提到死法嗎？
She didn't tell me I'd die till the end of the session.
沒有，她到最後才告訴我
I wasn't gonna waste a whole other hour there!
我不想再跟她耗1小時
I've only got a week left.
我只剩1星期了
I've really gotta start living now!
我得開始享受人生
（汽車與駕駛）
Hey,everyone.
大家好
Well,today's my first lecture...
我今天第一次上課
and I wanted to try it out on you guys. Do you mind?
想找你們演練一下，可以嗎？
No,that'd be great!
好啊 沒問題
"There are three primary theories concerning sediment flow rate.
沉積速率有三個主要理論
Each of these theories can be further subcategorized into two..."
每一個還可以細分為兩個…
This is it. This is what's gonna kill me.
我就是這樣死的
"...subcategories. The first of these subcategories is.."
類別，第一個是…
Are there naked chicks on that piece of paper?
羅斯，你那張紙上有裸女嗎？
No. Why?
沒有，怎麼了？
I never seen a guy stare so hard at something that didn't have chicks on it.
我沒見過紙上沒有裸女 男人還會死盯著看
好…
"There are three primary theories...
沉積速率有...
concerning sediment flow rate.
三個主要理論
Each of these theories...
每一個...
can be further subcategorized...
還可以細分...
into.."
為兩個…
Why don't you open with a joke?
不如以笑話開場
Open with a joke? It's a university, not a comedy club.
以笑話開場？ 那是大學，不是夜總會
Wait a minute,hold the phone.
等一下，且慢
You're not talking about Chuckles University?
是咯咯竊笑大學嗎？
Come on,we're kidding.
好 開玩笑的啦
You know what might make it less boring?
你知道怎樣會比較不無聊？
Thank you.
謝謝你喔
Some visual aids.
運用影像輔助
-You know what's a good visual aid? -Don't say naked chicks.
你知道哪種影像輔助最好？ 別跟我說裸女
Why not?
為什麼不行？
I don't even know why I talk to you guys about it.
真不知道我幹嘛找你們商量
I'm just gonna do it on my own, with no naked chicks.
我自己解決，不必用裸女
That's the way I did it till I was 19.
我19歲之前就是那樣
All right,20.
好吧，20歲
Twenty-three.
23歲
Any good mail?
有有用的信嗎？
Something from the Screen Actors Guild.
有，演員工會寄信給你
It's probably a residual check. Can you open it? I got....
可能是重播費 你幫我拆一下，我…
"Benefits lapsed."
保險中止
That's weird.
怪了
I don't remember being in a movie called Benefits Lapsed.
我沒演過這部片
It's not a check. Your health insurance expired because...
這不是支票 你的健保失效了，因為…
-you didn't work enough last year. -Let me see that.
你去年的工作時數不夠 我看看
Oh,I can't believe this!
不會吧
This sucks!
好爛喔
When I had insurance, I could get hit by a bus...
有保險時我可以被車撞
or catch on fire,you know?
或是被火燒
And it wouldn't matter. Now I gotta be careful?
都無所謂，現在卻得小心？
I'm sorry. There's never a good time to have to...
真可惜，被火燒這種事…
stop catching on fire.
停了總是不好
All right,well...
好吧
I guess I gotta go see my agent.
我得找工作了 我去見經紀人
Make sure to look both ways before you cross the street.
過馬路要小心左右來車
"Make sure to look both ways before you cross the street."
嘰哩瓜啦劈里啪啦
Hey,you're still alive!
菲比，你還活著
How are you feeling?
感覺如何？
It's so exhausting,waiting for death.
等死好累喔
Oh, by the way, do you think you..
對了，你能不能…
What are you doing?
菲比，你幹什麼？
Preparing you for.. Didn't you think I was dead?
我在替你做心理… 你沒有以為我死了嗎？
Did that not come off?
我裝得不像嗎？
Yeah, scared the hell out of me. I thought we'd lost you forever.
像，我嚇死了 我還以為我們永別了
-You wanna lie down? -Yeah,thanks.
你要不要睡一下？ 好，謝謝
Can you do me a favor?
對了，幫我一個忙
Wake me up in a couple hours.
兩個小時後叫我
You know, if you can.
如果還叫得醒的話
摩妮卡
Did you take these back?
這是你擺回去的？
I liked them so much that I bought some for myself.
不是，我很喜歡 就去買了一對
They're really great, aren't they?
真的很好看對吧？
I love them.
我好喜歡
Nice try.
想耍詐
How'd the lecture go?
課上得怎樣？
It went great.
很順利
And I didn't need any jokes or naked chicks either.
既不需要笑話，也不需要裸女
That's great. I'm sorry we weren't supportive before.
太好了 抱歉之前沒有好好幫忙
I knew I just had to let the material speak for itself.
我就知道教材充實最重要
Everyone's all, "Ross, you have to be funny and sexy."
每個人都說 「你得表現得風趣又性感」
Well, I proved them wrong!
我證明他們錯了
And now I'm gonna pass the news on to Joey and Chandler.
我現在就去告訴喬伊和錢德
-That you're not funny or sexy? -That's right!
說你不風趣也不性感？ 沒錯
-Hey, Estelle, listen.. -Well, well, well.
艾絲黛，聽著…
Joey Tribbiani.
喬伊崔比亞尼
So you came back,huh?
回來了是吧？
They think they can do better, but they all...
每個人都以為走比較好 但最後都...
come crawling back to Estelle.
爬回來求艾絲黛
What are you talking about?
你在說什麼？
I never left you. You've always been my agent.
我哪有離開 你一直是我的經紀人
Really?
是嗎？ 是啊
Oh, well, no harm no foul.
我沒惡意，你別在意
Look, you gotta get me some work. I lost my health insurance.
艾絲黛，你得幫我找工作 我的健保沒了
All right, first thing we gotta do: damage control.
好，首先得做傷害控制
-Why? -Well,I think...
為什麼？ 我覺得...
someone out there...
可能有人...
may have been bad-mouthing you all over town.
在到處中傷你
The bastard!
不要臉
（紐約大學）
We're early. The lecture doesn't end for 15 minutes.
我們來早了 還有15分鐘才下課
-But we could sneak in and watch. -Yeah,we could.
我們可以溜進去看 好
Hey, look. There's some Kappa Kappa Deltas. I was a Kappa.
看，KD姐妹會的人 我以前也是
Hey,sisters.
學妹好
Wow,we really are bitches.
我們還真的很討人厭
Right. So when Rigby got his samples back from the laboratory...
好，瑞格比從實驗室 取回樣本後
he made a startling discovery.
有了驚人的發現
What he believed to be igneous was, in fact, sedimentary.
他原以為那是火山物質 其實是沉積物
Imagine his consternation when..
他的驚愕不難…
Oh, bloody hell.
糟糕
So Estelle lined up a bunch of auditions for me tomorrow.
明天艾絲黛幫我排了一堆試鏡
And I'll have my health insurance back in no time.
我很快就能重新加入健保
That's great, but shouldn't you be on the toilet right now?
太好了 但你現在應該去蹲馬桶吧？
-What's wrong with you? -Nothing.
什麼？ 你是怎麼了？ 沒什麼
I got this blinding pain in my stomach when I was lifting weights before.
我剛才舉啞鈴時 肚子突然一陣劇痛
And then I passed out...
然後就昏倒了
and I haven't been able to stand up since.
而且一直站不起來
But I don't think it's anything serious.
不過應該沒什麼
This sounds like a hernia. Go to the doctor.
這應該是疝氣，你得去看醫生 我才不要
No way. If I go to the doctor, it'll be for this thing sticking out of my stomach!
就算要去看醫生 也是因為肚子這裡突出來
That's a hernia.
那就是疝氣
Why'd I have to start working out again?
我為什麼要恢復健身？
Damn you, 15s!
爛啞鈴
What the hell are you doing?
你在搞什麼？
Look,I was nervous.
我很緊張
You guys had me all worried I was gonna be boring.
你們害我擔心我會很無聊
I got up there and they were all, like, staring at me.
我上了台，學生都盯著我看
I opened my mouth and this British accent just came out.
結果我一開口就是英國腔了
Yeah, and not a very good one.
而且還很矬
Will you, please...?
別再說了
Dr. Geller? Kurt Rathman.
蓋勒博士，寇特拉斯曼
I'm a paleontology professor here.
古生物學系教授
Do you have a moment to talk about your lecture?
可以聊聊你的課嗎？
I'm sorry, I've got plans with my sister.
抱歉，我和舍妹有約
Monica Geller.
摩妮卡蓋勒
Right. Will you excuse us for one moment?
是的，失陪一下
-What are you doing? -You can have an accent, but I can't?
你幹什麼？ 你能裝我就不能裝？
Top of the morning to you, laddies!
小伙子早啊
Would you just please stop?
別鬧了
Yes,yes,Bombay is very, very nice this time of year.
是的，這個季節的孟買 灰常怡人
Hey, will you grab me a cruller?
幫我點個小煎餅
Sit down!
坐下啦
Will you go to the hospital?
我拜託你去看醫生
Hernia operations cost...
大哥，疝氣手術…
a lot probably,okay?
應該很貴
Besides,it's getting darker and more painful. That means it's healing.
而且它越來越黑，越來越痛 就表示有在好
Look, I'll loan you the money.
我借你錢
Just go to the hospital and let's just get that thing...
趕快去醫院把它…
pushed back in.
塞回去
Thank you, but it'd take me forever to pay you back.
謝謝，但我要很久才能還你
I don't want that hanging over my head.
我不想惦記這件事
Besides,when my insurance kicks in...
而且只要健保恢復
I can get all the free operations I want.
我就可以動各種免費手術
I'll probably start with that laser eye surgery.
我打算先去做眼睛雷射手術
What's going on?
怎麼了？
Joey's got a hernia, but it's nothing a little laser eye surgery won't fix.
喬伊的疝氣很嚴重 不過動個眼睛雷射手術就好了
I'm telling you, if I put my hand on my stomach...
真的，把手壓在這裡...
it doesn't hurt that bad.
就沒那麼痛
Hey, maybe you'll die!
搞不好你會死
Chandler, I'm scared.
錢德，我怕了
No, we can go together.
我們可以一起走
Just don't wait too long, because I'm out of here sometime before Friday.
但不要拖太久 我星期五之前就會掛掉
But I don't want to die.
但是我不想死
It'll be fun. We'll come back and haunt these guys!
不，會很好玩 我們可以回來嚇他們
Wait. Could I come back and haunt Monica and Rachel when they're in the shower?
等等，我可以趁摩妮卡 和瑞秋洗澡時回來嗎？
-That's my girlfriend. -Hey,I'm dead!
那是我的女朋友 我都死了
-Give me them! -No, they are mine!
給我 不要，這是我的
-You stole them from me! -You stole them from me!
是你偷我的 你才偷我的
Give me them!
拿來
Just wanna each take one?
要不要一人一個？
Yeah, that seems fair. We never use them.
很公平，反正也沒用過
Look, I really need some help, okay?
聽著，你們真的得幫我
Why did I have to speak in a British accent?
為什麼我要說英國腔？
What do I do?
我該怎麼辦？
Why don't you call Mummy and Daddy?
去問爸爸媽媽呀
I'm serious! Someone's gonna find out and then they're never gonna offer me a job.
我說真的，我遲早會被揭穿 教書的事就泡湯了
Why don't you phase it out? Yeah, phase the accent out.
慢慢把口音改掉
People will think you're adjusting to life in America.
別人會以為你在適應美國生活
Come on. No one will even notice.
是啊，根本不會有人注意
They're probably not even listening to you.
搞不好根本沒人在聽
They're not listening to me?
沒人在聽我講話？
Of course they're listening to you.
當然有人在聽
Everybody listens to you.
每個人都在聽你講話
Monica,do you think I should try this phasing-out thing?
你真的覺得我慢慢改嗎？
I think you look fine.
我覺得你很帥啊
Whenever you're ready.
好了就開始 好
Hey,Timmy.
提米
I've got a surprise...
我有個驚喜...
for you.
給你
Hold it. I'm sorry.
停，抱歉
The surprise is a new swing set. If you could play it less intense.
這個驚喜是一組新鞦韆 別演得這麼凝重
Oh,yeah. Sure, no problem.
好，沒問題
Just hold on one second.
等我一下
Hey,Timmy.
提米
I've got a surprise for you!
我要給你一個驚喜
Oh, my God!
天哪
So that's why I feed my dog Purina One.
所以我都餵我的狗吃跑路
Pick up a bag today.
今天就去搬一包吧
-That's where you pick up the bag. -Exactly.
這時候你要把它搬起來 沒錯
The line is, "Pick up a bag," so you need to pick up the bag.
不是，台詞是搬一包 所以你得把它搬起來
Or I could just point to it.
或是用指的
Purina One. Point to a bag today.
嘰哩呱哇  今天就去指一包吧
I didn't get it, did I?
我沒過，對吧？
-No. -Yeah.
沒有 好
Joey Tribbiani.
你好，我是喬伊崔比亞尼
I'm here to audition for "Man."
我來應徵…的人
You mean "Dying Man."
垂死的人嗎？ 沒錯
-Do it one more time. -Really? Really? Okay.
快，再打一次 真的要打？好
Hello, Ross? This is Dr. McNeely from the Fake Accent University.
羅斯你好 我是假口音大學的麥尼利博士
We'd like you to come onboard full-time!
我們想聘你當專任教授
Listen to this!
聽我說
My reading was wrong. I'm not going to die.
預言錯了，我不會死了
Really? How do you know?
真的？你怎麼知道？
My psychic is dead!
因為我的靈媒死了
She must have read the cards wrong.
她一定是看錯牌了
I'm sorry.
我很遺憾
Better her than me.
總比我死好
Hey,let's bake cookies!
我們來烤餅乾
Listen, I'm really glad you got the part.
恭喜你拿到這個角色
Are you sure you can do this?
你真的能演嗎？
And thanks for coming with me.
謝謝你陪我來
And thanks again for helping me take a shower.
還有謝謝你幫我洗澡
Now,is that "never talking about it again"?
這樣叫絕口不提嗎？
We're ready for you.
喬伊，都準備好了
This is Alex. He'll be playing your son.
這是亞歷，他演你的兒子
Hi,Alex.
你好
As you can see,my hands are not in my pants.
我的手可沒塞在褲子裡
好
All right, Alex. Now, when Joey says his line...
亞歷克斯，當喬伊說到
"Take good care of your mama, son," that's your cue to cry. Got it?
「好好照顧你媽媽」 你就要哭，懂嗎？
All right, let's do this.
好，來吧
Scene five, take one.
第五場，第一次
And action!
開始
Take good care of your mama, son.
兒子，好好照顧你媽媽
Come on, son.
拜託啦
Your mama's good people.
你媽是個好人
Cut! Alex, remember, you're supposed to cry.
停！ 亞歷克斯，這裡應該要哭
Can you cry for us this time?
你這次可以哭嗎？
All right. From the top.
好吧 好，重來
Scene five, take two.
第五場，第二次
Take 36 is up.
第卅六次要來了
Let's try this again.
再來一次
You ready,Joe?
喬伊，你好了嗎？
One thing, is it all right if I scream...
請問一下，你喊開始前
right up until you say, "Action"?
我可以大叫嗎？
Sure.
可以
-Action! -Take good care of your mama,son.
開始 兒子，好好照顧你媽媽
Cut!
卡
I'm sorry. Why don't you lift up your shirt? Take a look at this, kiddo.
抱歉…喬伊，你把衣服掀開來 小鬼你看
We have a crying child! Roll the damn cameras!
有小孩哭了，攝影機快拍
-Hello, is Ross there? -No,he's not. Can I take a message?
羅斯在嗎？ 他不在，你要留言嗎？
Yes, this is Russell, Ross' divorce lawyer.
好，我是羅斯的離婚律師
Since I haven't heard from him, I assume he's giving the marriage a try.
我想一直沒有他的回音 他應該是想試著經營這段婚姻
Ross got married again?
羅斯又結婚了？
All right, keep going. We are phasing the accent out.
繼續，慢慢改掉口音
Phasing it out.
慢慢改掉
"So without retesting their results in the laboratory...
要不是進實驗室重新化驗結果
the team would never have identified...
研究小組也不會發現
the initial errors in their carbon dating...
原先的碳14定年結果...
analysis."
有誤
Were there any questions at this point?
到這裡有問題嗎？
What's happening to your accent?
請說 你的口音怎麼沒了？
Come again? What's this nonsense?
再說一次，你說什麼？
All right. I'm not English.
好吧，我不是英國人
I'm from Long lsland.
我是長島人
I was really nervous, and the accent...
我一緊張就...
just came out.
冒出那個腔調了
I'm sorry.
很抱歉
So if we could just get back to the lecture.
回到課堂上來
Were there any questions?
有任何問題嗎？
About paleontology?
古生物學的問題
I was just trying to make a good first impression.
我只是想留下良好的第一印象
Obviously, I screwed up. But what you guys think of me is important...
但我顯然搞砸了 但你們對我的看法很重要
because I'm hoping to get a permanent job here.
因為我想成為專任教授
So if you'd just give me another chance to make a good impression..
如果你們肯再給我一次機會 製造好感…
Ross! Are you crazy?
羅斯！你瘋了嗎？
I am still your wife? Were you just never gonna tell me?
我還是你的老婆？ 你想瞞我一輩子嗎？
What the hell is wrong with you?
你是哪裡有病？
I could just kill you!
我真想宰了你
Well, hello, Rachel!
瑞秋你好
You've really done this before?
你真的玩過？
You just take a big, big swing,okay?
你就用力K下去
Now, don't hold back.
不要手軟
What are you doing?
你們在幹嘛？
We're just celebrating that Joey got his health insurance back.
慶祝喬伊的健保恢復
Oh, all right.
好
See? Now let's try one without the helmet.
看吧，脫掉頭盔再來一次